A Guide to the Paul Ehrlich papers FA135
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, Speeches, and Lectures
  - Herken, Hans, "Paul Ehrlich, Pioneer of Chemotherapy" [an address], 1976 March 25 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Schwerin, Gunther K., Speech given at Rockefeller University, 1978 November (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - "Forscher für das Leben" (On the occasion of the 125th birthday Celebration for Paul Ehrlich), 1979 March 14 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Witkop, Bernard, "Paul Ehrlich and his Times - Some thoughts on the History and Philosophy of Science and on German-Jewish Assimilation" [A lecture delivered at the Leo Baeck Institute in New York], 1986 April 9 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Doerr, H.W., "Des Konzept der Irnmunabwehr von Paul Ehrlich" [Lecture for the 500th meeting of the Frankfurt Medical Society], 1995 June 21 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Stern, Prof. Fritz, (Text of the original talk given at the opening of the Paul Ehrlich Institute), 1996 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Witkop, Prof. Bernhard, "Paul Ehrlich and His Time", Leo Baeck Institute, New York, 1996 April 18 (Box 62, Folder 13)
- Articles, Newsclippings, and Manuscripts
  - "Paul Ehrlich in Freiburg" I [Special Edition of Historical Medical Journal], undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - "Paul Ehrlich in Freiburg" II [Special Edition of Historical Medical Journal], undated (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Dissertation - Paul Ehrlich, 1878 June 17; 2 copies (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Ehrlich's Report about the Institute für Serumforschung u. Prüfung in Berlin, 1896-1899 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Klinisches Jahrbuch, [Clinical Yearbook], Jena, 1898 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Ehrlich's report about the institute für Serumforschung u. Prüfung in Berlin and the Institute for Experimental Therapie in Frankfurt, 1899-1900 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Klinisches Jahrbuch, Bericht über Thätigkeit des Königl. Instituts für Serumforschung zu Steglitz, [Report about the Royal Institute for Serum Research], 1900 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - "Vossische Zeitung", Berlin, September 11, 1902 [Ehrlich's recent research on poison bacteria and immunity], 1902 September 11 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - "Berichte der Deutschen Chemischen Gesellschaft" [Reports of the German Chemical Association - About the present state of Chemotherapy], 1908 October 31 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - "Beilage der [?] Presse" [Supplement to Der Presse], undated (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - List of six articles regarding Paul Ehrlich's Contributions, 1907-1976 (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Frankfurter Zeitung, articles from August 21 and 26, 1915, 1915 August 21 1915 August 26 (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Denkschrift des Ministeriums des Innern [Memorial Publication of the Minister of the Interior], 1918 (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - New York Academy of Medicine [Article on Paul Ehrlich Mementos], 1951 December 5 (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Chain, E.B., "Development of Anti-bacterial Chemotherapy" in The Times Science Review, Spring 1954 (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - Erlenbach, Dr. Michael, "Ehrlich - Behring" in Hoechst Farben-Post, 1954 March 16 (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - "Frankfurter Festakt für Helfer der Menschheit" in Frankfurter Rundschau [Frankfurt Celebration to Help Mankind], 1954 March 15 (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - Film text - "Dr. Ehrlich's Zauberkugel", 1954 March 2 (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - Ullman, Ludwig, "Des Lebens und Charakterbild eines grosser Mannes" in Deutsches Medizinisches Journal, April 1, 1954 [t.s.], 1954 April 1 (Box 63, Folder 19)
  - Newsclippings from 1954 (Box 63, Folder 20)
  - Pinkus, Hermann M.D., "In Commemoration of the 100th Anniversary of the Birth of Paul Ehrlich" in The American Journal of Clinical Pathology vol. 24, No. 7, 1954 July (Box 63, Folder 21)
  - Nuckolls, James G., "Ehrlich's formula: A + 4G's = Successful Research" in The New Physician, vol. 13, pp. A95-A96, 1964 March (Box 63, Folder 22)
  - Schneider-Römheld, Walter, "Steglitzer Institut für Serumforschung" in Steglitzer Heimat, 1965 January-June (Box 63, Folder 23)
  - Pelner, Louis, "Paul Ehrlich, M.D., (1854-1915). "Great Theoretician and Benefactor of Mankind" in New York State Journal of Medicine, Oct. 1, 1971, pp. 2331-2336 (Box 63, Folder 24)
  - Hirsch, James G. and Beate I. Hirsch, "Paul Ehrlich and the Discovery of the Eosinophil" in Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung, March 3, 1979 (Box 63, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper clipping of Paul Ehrlich Exhibit in Hoechst for his 125th Birthday, 1979 (Box 63, Folder 26)
  - Rubin, Lewis P., "Styles in Scientific Explanation: Paul Ehrlich and Svante Arrhenius on Immunochemistry" in Journal of the History of Medicine, 1980 October (Box 63, Folder 27)
  - Stern, F., "Paul Ehrlich in His Time: A Historian's View" Current Topics in Biomedical Research, 1988 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Witkop, Bernhard, "Science, Technology and Society in the Time of Alfred Nobel" Nobel Symposium 52, 1981 August 17-22 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Paul Ehrlich newsclippings, 1910-1980 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Cambrosio, Alberto, "Image et controverse scientifique dans les premières théories immunologiques" in Usages de l'image au XIX siecle. Paris: Créaphis, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Travis, Anthony, "Science as Receptor of Technology: Paul Ehrlich and the Synthetic Dyestuffs Industry" in Science in Context pp. 383-408, 1989 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Deutsche Bundesbank advertisement regarding new 200DM Banknote in Stern Magazin pp. 94-95, 1990 June 13 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Deutsche Bundesbank advertisement regarding new 200DM Banknote in Der Spiegel pp. 102-103, 1990 August 6 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Hain, Ingeborg, "Des Musikjournal" in Bayerischer Rundfunk, 1990 August 20 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - "Die Jagd nach der Zauberkugel" [The Hunt for the Magic Bullet] in Mein Betrieb, p. 3, 1990 October (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - "Paul Ehrlich" in Merkur Extra, 1990 November 9 (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Hoechst Advertisement regarding the Deutsche BundesBank Paul Ehrlich Banknote, Frankfurter Allgemeine Magazin, pp. 4-5, 1991 May 24 (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Rappuoli, Rino, "Vom Labor zur Klinik - Die Erfahrung mit Pertussis - Vakzine" [From Laboratory to the Clinic-The Experience with Pertussis - Vaccine], 1991 (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Wiedemann, Bernd, "Hat Unsere Gesellschaft sich des Namens Paul Ehrlich würdig erwiesen? " [Has Our Society made itself worthy of the name Paul Ehrlich] Chemotherapie Journal, 1992 April (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - "Zauberkugeln gegen Parasiten" [Magic Bullet to Fight Parasites] in Deutschland in Ost und West, 1990 July (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - Silverstein, Arthur, "The Heuristic Value of Experimental Systems", 1993, t.s. (Box 64, Folder 15)
  - Prusiner, Stanley B., "Prion Biologie und Prion Krankenheiten: Lachende Kannibalen, Rinderwahnsinn und Wissenschaftliche Häresie" [Prion Biology and Prion Sickness: Laughing Cannibals, Madcow Disease and the Scholarly Heretic], 1995 March 14 (Box 64, Folder 16)
  - Rough Draft of Phil Gerhard Venzmer, t.s., undated (Box 64, Folder 17)
  - "Thorough Thinking Comes Before The Experiment", t.s., undated (Box 64, Folder 18)
  - Pinkus M.D., Herman, "Paul Ehrlich and his Impact on Dermato-Syphilology", t.s., undated (Box 64, Folder 19)
  - "Die Welt dankt zwei grosser Helfern" [The World Thanks Two Large Helpers] Rundschau, 1961 March 15 (Box 64, Folder 20)
  - "Du bist der Hüter deines Bruders" [Newspaper Article], undated (Box 64, Folder 21)
  - "Vier Jahrzehnte Hauptwache" [Newspaper Article], undated (Box 64, Folder 22)
  - "NY Academy of Sciences Erhält Büste von Paul Ehrlich" [NY Academy of Sciences Receives Bust of Paul Ehrlich] [Newspaper Article], undated (Box 64, Folder 23)
  - "Bust of Ehrlich Given to Academy" [Newspaper Article], undated (Box 64, Folder 24)
- Reprints and Bibliographies
  - "50 Jahre Neuropathologie in Deutschland", 1885-1935 [On the life and work of Carl Weigert] (Box 64, Folder 25)
  - Title pages of publication by Paul Ehrlich Institute in Langen, 1891 (Box 64, Folder 26)
  - "Artzebreife aus vier Jahrhunderten" [Doctor's letters over four centuries], 1920 (Box 64, Folder 27)
  - "Deutsches Biographisches Jarbuch" [German Biographical Yearbook], 1925 (Box 64, Folder 28)
  - Valer, Barbu M.D., "What Schools of Psychoanalysis are There? " [Lecture], undated (Box 64, Folder 29)
  - Bender, George A., "A History of Medicine in Pictures-Ehrlich Chemotherapy is Launched", undated (Box 64, Folder 30)
  - Loewi O., "Small Talk on Pharmacology" [Presented at the Annual Pharmacology Dinner, Atlantic City, Thursday evening], 1950 April 20 (Box 64, Folder 31)
  - Dale, Sir Henry, "Paul Ehrlich" in British Medical Journal, pp. 559-563, 1954 March 20 (Box 64, Folder 32)
  - "Errinerungen an Paul Ehrlich" [Remembrances of Paul Ehrlich] in Der Hautarzt, pp. 127-134, 1954 March 14 (Box 64, Folder 33)
  - Vonkennel, Dr. J. "Die Medizinische" in Medizinische, pp. 348-352, 1954 March 13 (Box 64, Folder 34)
  - Pinkus, Hermann M.D., "In Commemoration of the 100th Anniversary of the Birth of Paul Ehrlich" The American Journal of Clinical Pathology, vol. 24, pp. 751-754, 1954 July 7 (Box 64, Folder 35)
  - Jokl, Ernst, "Paul Ehrlich - Man and Scientist" in Bulletin of the New York Academy of Medicine, vol. 30, pp. 968-975, 1954 December (Box 64, Folder 36)
  - Galdston, Iago, "Ehrlich, Biologist of Deep and Inspired Vision" in The Scientific Monthly, vol. 79, pp. 395-399, 1954 December (Box 64, Folder 37)
  - Jokl, Ernst, "Physiology of Exercise" Journal of Health-Physical Education-Recreation, 1955 March (Box 64, Folder 38)
  - "A Fiftieth Anniversary Commemorative Tribute to Paul Ehrlich, with Two Letters to American Friends", 1910-1911 (Box 64, Folder 39)
  - Biberstein, Hans, "In Memorium: Rudolf A. Stern", 1963 (Box 64, Folder 40)
  - "Gesamtverzeichnis des deutschsprachigen Schrifttums (GV) 1911-1965," [The Complete Record of German Speaking Literature] (Box 64, Folder 41)
  - "In Memorium: Paul Ehrlich" [Newsclipping], 1966 (Box 64, Folder 42)
  - Schneck, Peter, "Die Briefe Paul Ehrlich's an den Moskauer Microbiologen Georgij Norbetovic Gabricevskij" NTM Schriftener, pp. 81-87, 1982 [The Paul Ehrlich Letter to the Moscow Microbiologist Georgij Norbetovic Gabricevskij] (Box 64, Folder 43)
  - Silverstein, Arthur M. "History of Immunology - Paul Ehrlich: The Founding of Pediatric Immunology", Cellular Immunology June 27, 1996 (Box 64, Folder 44)
- Brochures, Pamphlets, and Journals
  - Hitchings, George H., "The Third Paul Ehrlich Lecture" (Box 64, Folder 45)
  - Basic Research as Forerunner of New Medications", Medicinal Research Reviews, vol. 11, pp. 1-15, 1991 (Box 64, Folder 45)
  - "Grandson, Recent Spa Visitor, Cites Honors for Dr. Ehrlich" [Newspaper Article], undated (Box 64, Folder 46)
  - "Arbeiten aus dem Königlichen Institut für Experimentelle Therapie, Frankfurt am Main" [Work from the Royal Institute for Experimental Therapy, Frankfurt am Main], undated (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - "Aus Theorie und Praxis das Chemotherapie" [Of the Theory and Practice of Chemotherapy], Leipzig, 1911 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Reichart, Walter A., "Gerhart Hauptman die Finisternisse" [The darkness of Gerhart Hauptman], 1947 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Zoph, Hans, Schweizer Monats Hefte. [Schweizer Monthly Publication] book 2, 1940 May (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - "Arbeiten aus dem Paul Ehrlich Institut dem Georg Speyer Haus und dem Ferdinand Blum Institut zu Frankfurt A.M. " [Works from the Paul Ehrlich Institute, the Georg Speyer House and the Ferdinand Blum Institute at Frankfurt am Main] volume 51, 1954 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Gans, Oscar, "Zür Erinnerung und zür Bessinnung" [To the memory and the contemplation], volume 11, 1954 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Der Hautarzt. "Chemotherapie bosartiger Tumoren" (article in a German) (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Dermatological journal dealing with Ehrlich - Chemotherapy and Malignant Tumors], 1954 March (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Deutsches Medizinisches Journal book 7, [Journal with articles on Ehrlich and Emil von Behring], 1954 April 1 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - "The Paul Ehrlich Hospital and Medical Centre", 1954 April (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Acta Haematologica - International Journal of Haematology. vol. II, No. 4, 1954 April (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - International Archives of Allergy and Applied Immunology, vol. 5, no. 2, 1954 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - "The Paul Ehrlich Hospital and Medical Centre, 1954 April (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Jokl, Ernst, "Alter und Leistung" [Age and Achievement], 1954 (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - [A Japanese Medical Journal] (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Lang-Hinrichsen, Dr. Dietrich, Sonderdruck aus Zeitschrift für gesamte Strafrechtswissenschaft [Reprint from the Special Publication for the study of the entire penal code], volume 2, 1961 (Box 65, Folder 15)
  - Nipperdey, Hans Carl, Archiv fiir die Civilistische Praxis [Archive for Civil Practice] [text on Theodor Süss], vol. 160, book 3, 1961 October (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - Frankel, Jonas, "Gottfried Keller und die Juden" in Bulletin des Leo Baeck Instituts. no. 18, 1962 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Hurwitz, Janina, "Paul Ehrlich als Krebsforscher" [Paul Ehrlich as Cancer researcher], Inaugural dissertation upon the achievement of a Doctorate of the medical faculty at the University of Zurich, 1962 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Schwerin, Kurt, "Marc Pinkus, Seine Schlesierbucherei und Seine Freundschaft mit Gerhart Hauptman" [Max Pinkus, his Schlesier book and his friendship with Gerhart Hauptman] in Bulletin des Leo Baeck Instituts. no. 18, 1962 August (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Stern, Fritz, [Professor of History at Columbia University] "In Memoriam Stefanie Schwerin", 1966 June 10 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Bahr, H.W., [compiled by] "1966 Paul Ehrlich Prize'in Cultural News from Germany, p. 16, 1966 March (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Hoechst Heute [Several short articles on Paul Ehrlich and Emil von Behring and Robert Koch], 1973 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Herken, Hans, "Paul Ehrlich, Pioneer of Chemotherapy" [Address at the dedication of the Paul Ehrlich Wing of the Arnold R. Meyer Institute of Biological Sciences], Thursday, March 25, 1976 [at the Wix Auditorium of the Weizmann Institute of Science, Rehovot, Israel], 1976 March 25 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - "Paul Ehrlich, Pioneer in Chemotherapy" in Rehovot pp. 35-40, vol. 8, no. 2, 1976-1977 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Bulletin des Leo Baeck Instituts. no. 56/57, 1980 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Parascandola, John, "The Theoretical Basis of Paul Ehrlich's Chemotherapy" in Journal of the History of Medicine and Allied Sciences, vol. XXXVI, no. 1, 1981 January (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - "Die Humorale Immunität im Forschungsansatz von Paul Ehrlich (1854-1915) " [The exemption of immunity in the initial research of Paul Ehrlich] [Inaugural dissertation upon the achievement of a doctorate from the medical faculty of the Christian Albrechts University at Kiel], 1982 March 15 (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - "Paul Ehrlich and His Times" in LBI New. p. 10, no. 52, Summer (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - "Paul Ehrlich Forscher für das Leben", 1981 (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Zappel, Albrecht, "Max Pinkus - Der Schlesische Unternehmer Seine Schlesierbibliothek" [Max Pinkus - The Schlesische Head of the Schlesier Library], book 8, 1992 December (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Paul Ehrlich Institute pamphlet [with a letter from Ehrlich to Professor Dr. Reinhard Kurth] (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - Warburg, Otto Heinrich, "Paul Ehrlich 1854-1915" in Die Sonderdruck Die Grossen Deutschen n.d. (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - "100 Jahre Paul Ehrlich-Institut" [100 Years of the Paul Ehrlich Institute], 1896-1996 (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - "The Paul Ehrlich Institute", 1996 (Box 66, Folder 18)
  - [A Japanese Journal], undated (Box 66, Folder 19)
- Synopses
  - "Briefe van Carl Weigert, Direktor, Senckenbergisches pathologisch-anatomisches Institut, Frankfurt a.M. " [Letters from Carl Weigert], 1888-1907 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - "Deutsche Auszeichnungen und Ernennungen Paul Ehrlichs", 1890-1911 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - "An den Vortragenden Rath Ministerium für Medicinal Angelegenheiten" Berlin, Dr. Schmidt, 1900 June 11 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Darmstaedter Correspondence, 1900-1914 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence regarding Carcinom studies, 1901-1914 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Special Edition by Benario Muncher Medizinische Wochenschrift. No. 46, 1912 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence regarding report by Paul Ehrlich about Dr. Braithwaites Paper, 1902-1915 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Death Notices and Obituaries of Paul Ehrlich, 1915 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - "Konigliches Institut für experimentelle Therapie zu Frankfurt", 1975 August 22 (Box 67, Folder 9)
- Photographs
  - Photos of Paul Ehrlich, undated (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Photos of Ehrlich, undated (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Photos of Ehrlich, undated (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Hedwig Pinkus at age 17, 1881 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Hedwig Pinkus, 1882 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Hedwig Pinkus' childhood house, undated (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Photograph of Hedwig Ehrlich at 35 years of age, 1899 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Picture of interior of Hedwig Pinkus house [2 copies], undated (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Photograph of Ehrlich's family and friends, undated (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Photograph "Die Bildhauerin Bianca Ehrlich mit einer Porträtbüste (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Paul Ehrlich" [A photograph of the sculptor Bianca Ehrlich with a portrait bust of Paul Ehrlich], undated (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Photo of Edmund Landau w/ children, Gottingen, 1915-1916 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Framed photo of Günther K. Schwerin in the U.S. - winter, 1937-1937 (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - Hedwig Ehrlich in Philadelphia, PA, 1941 (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Photographs of tribute to Paul Ehrlich, undated (Box 68, Folder 14)
  - Paul Ehrlich Institute photographs, undated (Box 68, Folder 15)
  - "Zur 100. Wiederkehr der Geburtstage von Paul Ehrlich und Emil v. Behring", 1954 March 13-16 (Box 68, Folder 16)
  - Paul Ehrlich booth at Chicago University of P.E. Exposition (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Schwerin-Jugend Bilder, undated (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Family Photos, 1895-1966 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Photograph of bronze medallion of the First International Congress of Immunology, 1971 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Photograph of Günther K. Schwerin, Beate I. Hirsch and Dr. James G. Hirsch in South Tyrol, Italy "Dick Hof", 1980 October 3 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - "Leihgaben Dr. Hans Schwerin, New York, zur Paul-Ehrlich Ausstellung", 1980 September 8 (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Photo of Prof. Hans-Dieter Brede, President of the Paul Ehrlich Institute, undated (Box 69, Folder 7)
- Memorabilia
  - Bronze Medallion struck for first International Congress of Immunology, undated (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Deutsche Bundesbank new bank notes announcement package, undated (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - Poster of Paul Ehrlich banknote for Union Investment Bank, undated (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Postage stamps of Ehrlich and Behring, undated (Box 69, Folder 11)
- Translations (Box 69)
  - "Zeitungsartikel" [Newspaper articles] "Paul Ehrlich, March 14, 1854-August 20, 1915 [Clippings book, mostly empty], 1854 March 14-1915 August 20 (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - "Feinberg's Studies on Carcinomas" [Translation], 1902 (Box 69, Folder 13)
  - Letters from Hedwig and Paul Ehrlich To Friedrich Althoff Translations by S. VonGoertz, 1895-1908 (Folder 14)
  - Letters from Hedwig and Paul Ehrlich To Friedrich Althoff Translations by S. VonGoertz, 1896 June 9 (Box 69, Folder 15)
  - Ehrlich's correspondence with Ministerial Directors of several Scientific Institutes in Germany, 1898-1904 (Box 69, Folder 16)
  - "Über den jetztigen Stand der Chemotherapie", [About the Current State of Chemotherapy], talk given to the German Chemical Society, 1908 October 31 (Box 69, Folder 16)
- Oversize material
  - [Framed picture of Ehrlich in his later years and a record collection], undated (Box 70)
  - [Framed pictures] (Box 71)
  - Advertisement for new 200 DM Banknote, Colored lithograph by Ernst Wilhelm Knippel of Schmeideberg 1840/45 with Bronze bust of Ehrlich, 1840-1945 (Box 72)
- Laboratory Notebooks
  - undated, black notebook "Italienisch"; cut pages in H.P. handwriting inserted; Handwriting: Hedwig Pinkus; 16.4 × 20.2 × 0.8 cm. (Box 73)
  - undated, black notebook; missing front cover; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 20.8 × 17.2 × 0.5 cm. (Box 73)
  - undated, black notebook; missing front cover; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 20.8 × 17.2 × 0.5 cm. (Box 73)
  - undated, black notebook; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 20.8 × 17.2 × 0.5 cm. (Box 73)
  - 1886 1888 undated, black notebook; cover from? Notebook glued on cover; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 20.8 × 17.2 × 0.5 cm. (Box 73)
  - undated, black notebook; missing part of cover; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 20.8 × 17.2 × 0.5 cm. (Box 73)
  - 1889, undated, notebook pages; no covers, pages loose; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 20.8 × 17.2 × 0.5 cm. (Box 73)
  - undated, black notebook; page from other notebook adhered to cover; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 20.8 × 17.2 × 0.5 cm. (Box 73)
  - undated, brown notebook "Aufsätze"; includes loose page inserts; Handwriting: Hedwig Pinkus; 16.4 × 20.2 × 0.8 cm. (Box 73)
  - undated, black notebook, dedicated "Porte bonheur à mon cher petit Mari"; covers missing; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 14.0 × 18.8 × 0.5 cm. (Box 73)
  - undated, black notebook; front cover damaged missing back cover; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 20.8 × 17.2 × 0.5 cm. (Box 73)
  - undated, black notebook; patient log; Handwriting: unknown; 16.8 × 21.0 × 0.5 cm. (Box 73)
  - undated, folder; clippings, reprints and notes by Ehrlich (Box 73)
  - undated, black notebook "Fittrung"; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 10.0 × 15.6 × 0.5 cm. (Box 74)
  - undated, perforated memo pad; no cover, gold leaf page edges; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 10.0 × 16.5 × 1.0 cm. (Box 74)
  - undated, black notebook; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 10.0 × 16.3 × 0.5 cm. (Box 74)
  - undated, black notebook; covers loose; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 10.2 × 17.0 × 1.2 cm. (Box 74)
  - 1884, undated, black notebook; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 10.5 × 16.7 × 0.6 cm. (Box 74)
  - 1884, undated, black notebook; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 9.8 × 16.3 × 0.5 cm. (Box 74)
  - 1893 1894, brown leather notebook; gold leaf page edges; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 8.6 × 13.4 × 0.9 cm. (Box 74)
  - 1885, black notebook, "Frosch"; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 10.0 × 16.5 × 0.6 cm. (Box 74)
  - 1885, undated, black notebook; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 10.2 × 16.5 × 0.5 cm. (Box 74)
  - 1885, black notebook; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 10.2 × 16.6 × 0.5 cm. (Box 74)
  - undated, black notebook; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 10.8 × 17.4 × 1.4 cm. (Box 74)
  - 1886, black notebook "Farbstoffe"; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 10.2 × 16.0 × 0.6 cm. (Box 74)
  - 1885, undated, loose notebook pages; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 10.2 × 16.0 × 1.5 cm. (Box 74)
  - 1884, black notebook; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 9.8 × 16.2 × 0.5 cm. (Box 74)
  - undated, brown notebook; Handwriting: Ehrlich; 10.8 × 17.0 × 2.0 cm. (Box 74)
- Blocke (Box 75)
- Blocke (Box 76)
- Reprints (Box 77)
- Reprints (Box 78)
- Reprints (Box 79)
- Translations Sponsored by RAC
  - [Reprint: "On Acquiring Diphtheria Antitoxin from the Blood Serum and Milk of Immunized Animals, "Paul Ehrlich and A. Wassermann] (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - [Reprint: "The Efficacy of Small Doses of Tuberculin Against Pulmonary Consumption", P. Guttmann and Paul Ehrlich] (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - [Correspondence: Handwritten: 60th Birthday, (To remove the]), 1914 May 24 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - [Reprint: "Medizinische Unterhaltung: Persönliche Erinnerungen an Paul Ehrlich", 1929 March 14 (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - [The Recent State of Carcinoma Research, Paul Ehrlich] (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - ["What is Known about the Action of Antitoxins", By Paul Ehrlich from the Institute for Serum Research and Serum Analysis in Steglitz] (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - [Paul Ehrlich to Christian Herter, 1909 July 10 (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - [The Recent State of Carcinoma Research, Paul Ehrlich] (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - [Chemotherapie by Paul Ehrlich] (Box 87, Folder 9)